<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Hello, World!</title>
    <link href="http://terryoy.github.io/misc/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://terryoy.github.io/misc/" />
    <updated>2021-03-30T22:34:14+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://terryoy.github.io/misc/</id>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LambdaChip Alonzo “Unboxing” (at WoodHouse BBQ)]]></title>
        <author><name>terryoy</name></author>
        <link href="http://terryoy.github.io/2021/03/lambdachip-alonzo--unboxing---at-woodhouse-bbq-.html"/>
        <published>2021-03-29T21:57:00+08:00</published>
        <updated>2021-03-30T22:34:14+08:00</updated>
        <id>http://terryoy.github.io/2021/03/lambdachip-alonzo--unboxing---at-woodhouse-bbq-.html</id>
        <category scheme="http://terryoy.github.io/tag/#embedded" term="embedded" label="embedded" />
        <category scheme="http://terryoy.github.io/tag/#hardware" term="hardware" label="hardware" />
        <content type="html" xml:base="http://terryoy.github.io/" xml:lang="en">
            <![CDATA[ <p>Since many people have to wait for their LamdbaChip Alonzo board to arrive, I&#39;m going to write an &ldquo;unboxing&rdquo; article about the dev board here and share an interesting story about it.</p>
<p>This is not the official article to LambdaChip and the Alonzo board. It&#39;s just that I&#39;m lucky enough to know for years the guys behind all these, who pay endless effort to make this product come true and keep improving. It&#39;s a great honor to be in the SZDIY community and share the highlight moments of this project.</p>

<h2 id="toc_0">The Release Announcement (at WoodHouse BBQ)</h2>
<p>Just a few days before the Chinese New Year of 2021, the LamdbaChip team decided to announce the Alonzo board after a long prepration for manufacturing. A group of friends in SZDIY gathered at WoodHouse BBQ(a famous Shenzhen BBQ restaurant) for the dinner, and in the atmosphere of beer and joy, co-founder <a href="https://lambdachip.com/articles/news/2">Rafael Lee</a> bring out several suites of the LamdbaChip Alonzo bundle version and give them out to everyone, and ask for everyone&#39;s opinion. </p>
<p>And this was what I&#39;ve got:</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-29-2256ZEZme6.png" alt="LambdaChip First Impression"/></p>

<h2 id="toc_1">The &ldquo;Un-unboxing&rdquo; experience</h2>
<p>Instead of getting a fine assembled box of the product(like you always do when you buy something), we got pieces of the every bits we need to assembled a final box of the bundle. So this unboxing is kind of like a &ldquo;time-reversed&rdquo; experience, (or &ldquo;inverting entropy&rdquo; as in the film <em>Tenet</em>), which you start with the pieces and end with a box.</p>
<p>First, the paper case as the last image. Then came the manual and the wires:</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2055bR6IVu.png" alt="LambdaChip manual and the wires"/></p>
<p>As you can see, there is the USB dongle for Type C, and the white wire with both USB Type C at each end. So it gives you to the flexibility to connect to a Type A or Type C receptable on PC or or Mobile or any other USB charger. There is another grey wire which is a JTAG connector for the Saruman Debugger. Also, there are some pieces of aclyric board in the plastic bag, which will make a protection case for the Alonzo board.</p>
<p>Then we get the foam holder and the boards: the <strong>Alonzo</strong> and the <strong>Saruman Debugger</strong>.</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2129gzXVU2.png" alt="Foam holder with boards"/>
<img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2226POKTbs.png" alt="Back of the board"/></p>
<p>For saving the cost,  we didn&#39;t get the TF card that comes with the bundle(also because we are so easy to get one in HuaQiangBei market), but we got a bag for carrying all the things you need to play with the Alonzo board.</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2130M5MtuE.png" alt="bag"/></p>
<p>Finally, we arrived at the beginning of &ldquo;the unboxing&rdquo; - the box!</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2111AomBZK.png" alt="Alonzo Bundle Box"/></p>

<h2 id="toc_2">The Assembled Board</h2>
<p>After I soldered the pins, and also assembled the aclyric case for the board, so here are some more closer look to the Alonzo board.</p>
<p><img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2112UIfSjk.png" alt="Assembleded Alonzo"/>
<img src="https://pic.lucki.cn/upics/2021-03-30-2233FvKetN.png" alt="Assembled Alonzo 1"/></p>
]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>